<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>untagged on Flugplatz</title>
    <link>flugplatz.github.io/tags/untagged/</link>
    <description>Recent content in untagged on Flugplatz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:29:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="flugplatz.github.io/tags/untagged/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is the BTree an efficient structure to model an orderbook?</title>
      <link>flugplatz.github.io/posts/btree_orderbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>flugplatz.github.io/posts/btree_orderbook/</guid>
      <description>The orderbook is an interesting object to model, likely to be dense with orders near the top of the book and sparser as we walk outwards towards the &amp;ldquo;stink bids&amp;rdquo;. While reading Database Internals: A Deep-Dive into How Distributed Data Systems Work 1, its low level discussion of BTree internals peaked my curiosity into the efficiency of using a BTree to model an orderbook. My main observations are:
It was presented as a disadvantage that file based databases have to marshall their data structures explicitly on disk while in-memory databases just malloc() memory chunks from an allocator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjusted t-stat for overlapping samples</title>
      <link>flugplatz.github.io/posts/adjusted_t-stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 19:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>flugplatz.github.io/posts/adjusted_t-stat/</guid>
      <description>When computing a regression coefficient we hopefully can reject the null hypothesis that there is no relationship between the dependent and independent variable ($ \beta_0 = 0 $). When evaluating a trading strategies returns we aim to reject the null hypothesis that they are unprofitable random noise around 0.
If we assume the distribution underlying the inputs are normal ($X_{0}$ for regression and $r_{t}$ for returns) we can use the t-stat to decide to reject these hypothesis&amp;rsquo; or not.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
